恶灵之泪
Mother Of Tears
轻点  慢慢来
Uh-huh. uh-huh. easy now.
-你还好吧  -下面有东西
- you okay? - hey there's something down here!
奥斯卡・德勒 1815
"oscar de la vall? 1815."
剪断铁链
Cut the chains.
我们把他重新埋葬在公墓的另一边吧
We'll rebury him on the other side of the cemetery...
稍晚动工
Later tonight.
骨灰瓮呢
And the urn?
放到我车上去吧
Put it in my car.
牧师  笑一个吧
- hang on monsignor. -
亲爱的米高
Dear michael...
今天我们在墓地外面
We found something alarming today...
找到了这个带有警告的物件
Right outside of the cemetery.
我现在把这个骨灰瓮交给你
I'm sending this urn over to you...
那样你可以细查下上面的条文
That you can examine its contents.
你对魔法历史和秘教学的认识
You know more about the history of magic...
比我要深厚得多
And esoteric sciences than I do...
希望你能消除
And I'm hoping you can deny...
我的忧虑
What I fear.
罗马古代艺术博物馆
Rome,Museum of Ancient Art
好一会儿没有见到他了
Not for a couple of hours.
-他得带保罗去看医生  -对啊
- he had to take paul to the doctor. - oh that's right.
我刚还在纳闷  他怎么不接我电话
I was wondering why he wasn't answering his cell.
过来  有些东西给你看
Come take a look at something.
什么
What?
来  我带你去看  跟我来
Here let me show you. come with me.
好吧
All right.
-是什么  -过来  我告诉你
- what is it? - come. I'll show you.
我知道现在很晚  但你真的需要看一下
I know it's late but you really need to check this out.
-真的?  -是的
- really? - yeah.
别老卖关子 是什么
Don't keep me hanging. what is it?
-好的  是一个骨灰瓮  -真的吗
- all right. it's an urn. - really?
是的
Yes.
-哪里来的  -维泰波的牧师布路卡斯寄来的
- where'd it come from? - viterbo. a monsignor brusca sent it.
同时还找到了一具1815年埋的棺材
They found it with a coffin buried in 1815.
-很惊奇对吧   -我从没看过这样的东西
- isn't this amazing? - I've never seen anything like this.
是的
I know.
米高的电话还是关机
Oh. michael's phone is still off.
你认为我们要趁他不在的时候冒险打开它吗
What do you think? should we risk opening it without him?
-别问我  -好吧
- don't ask me. -  yeah right.
我们只要打开看看  我不会碰那封信的
You know what? we're just gonna open it up and I won't touch the letter.
-好吧  -好的
- deal. - okay.
-动手吧  -好的
- let's do it. - all right.
你要帮忙吗
Do you need help?
不  我自己来好了
No I think I'm okay.
啊  妈的
Ow! damn it!
没事吧  怎么了
Are you okay? what is it?
我割到自己了  皮外伤而已
Aah. I cut myself. I'll be all right.
-没事的  准备好了吗  -好了
- it's okay. are you ready? - yeah.
-好了  -动手
- okay. - let's do it.
-开工  -这样吗
- let's go. - like this?
对  有点重
Yeah. it's a little tough.
好的  行了
All right. yeah there you go.
小心点
Careful.
是的
Yeah.
仔细看着这刀柄
Take a careful look at the hilt.
-告诉我你看到什么  -有宝石装饰
- tell me what you see. - the gemstone settings.
中世纪工艺  对吧
It's a medieval technique isn't it?
很好  很有可能是十三世纪的
Very good. thirteenth century most likely.
看  三个雕像
Look. three statues.
-有点骇人  -是的
- that's kind of scary. - yeah.
-拿着  -你来吧
- you take it. - there you go.
好的  那里还有
Okay. oh there's more.
看看这个
Look at this. okay.
都保存得很好
They're so well-preserved.
-对啊  -看看这些字
- yeah. - look at this writing.
-这里还有  -是吗
- hey there's more. - yeah?
这像是某种护符
This is some kind of talisman.
看得懂吗
Can you read the writing?
不  我不能即时翻译
No not offhand.
这是种古语言
It's some ancient language.
你知道吗
You know what?
去找本亚拉姆和迈锡尼字典  好吗
Go and grab the aramaic and mycenaean dictionaries will you?
-好的  -他会希望我们把这个迷解开的
- yeah. - he'll want us to move on this right away.
-好的  -谢谢
- okay. - thank you.
不  不
- -  no! no!
救我  不
- help me! no! -
快跑
Go now.
Go now!
救命  请救救我
Hello. help! please help me!
你看到四个人了  你描述他们是"丑陋畸形"  是吗
You saw four people and they were to use your words "deformed"?
我看不到他们的脸  但是
I didn't see their faces but...
他们移动姿势怪异无比
There was something very strange about the way they moved.
-怎么说  -就像是
- how so? - it was like-
他们把她活活撕碎了
God they tore her to bits.
-四周是血  -等等
- the blood it was- - wait.
-他们怎么移动  -有点弯腰驼背的样子
- how did they move? - well they were sort of hunched over.
但我只看到他们几秒而已
But I only saw them for a few seconds.
-所以那里有三个怪人  -对  还有一只猴子
- so there were three deformed people. - yes and a monkey.
-一只猴子?  -是的  它要来抓我
- a monkey? - yes. it was chasing me.
好的
Okay.
萨拉
Sarah.
你到底在学院里从事什么工作  萨拉
So what exactly do you do for the institute sarah?
我的专业是文物修补和考古学
I'm studying art restoration and archaeology.
那你维修过那些还没启封
And did you manage to catalog these pieces of art...
-就被偷盗的文物吗  -没有
- that were stolen before they were taken away? - no.
我们才刚刚开始检查它们
We were just starting to examine them.
听着  要说的我都说了
Look I told you everything I know.
我可以回家了吗
Can I please go home now please?
-萨拉  -不  没事的  让他进来吧
- sarah! - no it's okay. let him in.
-米高  天啊  -萨拉  你没事吧
- michael. oh   my god. - sarah! hey are you okay?
-米高  那太恐怖了  还有吉塞尔  她  -没事的  没事的
- michael it was horrible. and giselle she- - shh. shh. it's okay.
没事的  我在这  没事的
It's okay. I'm here now. it's okay.
你好  我是米高・皮尔斯  博物馆馆长
Hi I'm michael pierce. I'm the director of the museum.
-我是安索・ 马奇  侦查科主任  -很好
- I am enzo marchi the head of this investigation. - great.
-我要带她回家  好吗 -当然可以  没问题
- look I'm gonna take her home now   okay? - of course. no problem.
-谢谢  -你还好吧
- thank you. - are you all right?
难以置信
I can't believe it.
你听过吗
Did you hear that?
她是个疯婆子
She's crazy.
你太爱盘问了  你知道吗
You're some detective you know?
-当然  -好好看着她
- sure. - go and keep an eye on her.
今晚我能在你家过夜吗
Can I stay at your place tonight?
我真的不想孤零零一个人
I really don't feel like being alone.
当然可以
Of course you can.
外面真冷
It's freezing outside.
-我可以点下火炉吗  -可以  我要去看一看保罗
- can I light a fire? - yeah sure. I'm just gonna check on paul.
好的
All right.
好极了  他睡得正香
Good. well he's still asleep.
今晚我身上发生了奇怪的事
Something very strange happened to me tonight.
我也不知道该怎么对你说
And uh I feel almost embarrassed to tell you about it.
什么
What?
答应我  你不会把我当疯子
Promise me you won't think I'm crazy.
-我保证  -好吧
- I promise. - all right.
我当时走投无路
I was trapped in there.
本来我是不可能活着离开那里的
And there was no way I was gonna get out of there alive.
-然后  -怎么了
- and then- - what?
算了  当我没说
Nah never mind.
继续  继续说
Come on. tell me.
接着
And then...
我听到脑海里有一道声音
I heard a voice in my head...
叫我快走
Telling me to go.
然后  砰的一声  门很瞬间打开了
And then- bam- the doors slammed open!
我是说  门瞬间打开了
I mean they were locked and they slammed open!
然后我...还有个女人
And l-and there was this woman too-
爸爸
Dad?
小老虎  你起来干什么啊
Hey tiger! what are you doing up? huh?
我以为你睡着了  过来
I thought you were asleep. ah come here.
-保罗  你好  -萨拉  你好
- hi paul. - hi sarah.
-你要热巧克力吗  -好的  我可以晚点睡吗
- do you want some hot chocolate? - yes. can I stay up late?
可以  你可以晚点睡
Yes you can stay up late.
选本你喜欢的书  然后我们带你到床上去
Let's choose one of your books and we'll take you to bed.
你想要哪本  这本吗  好的
Which one are you gonna get? this one? okay.
我待会把它们都拿进房间给你  来吧  回到床上去
I'm gonna come in with the hot chocolate now. come on. back to bed.
马上就来  好吗
Coming in a second all right?
我真搞不清楚
I just can't get my head around it.
为什么他们要杀死吉塞尔
Why did they have to kill giselle?
那个骨灰瓮有什么玄机
What was so important about that urn?
照你这样说  他们可能是护身兽
Well from what you told me they could be talismans.
听着   我明天早上要去见布路卡斯牧师
Look I'm gonna go and see monsignor brusca tomorrow morning.
或者他可以透露更多资信
Maybe he can shed some more light on it.
你怎么认识他的
How do you know him?
他几年前来到伦敦讲授精神学
Well he came to london a few years ago to lecture on spiritualism.
理所当然  他当时是
And he's meant to be a leading
是神秘学和超自然科学的权威
Authority on mysticism and the occult sciences-
科学?  拜托  你不会相信这些废话吧
"sciences"? come on. you don't believe in that crap.
-超自然吗  -对
- the occult? - yeah.
半信半疑吧
Well maybe maybe not.
怎么了
- hmph. -what?
我刚才只是
I was just-
难道你不相信超出人类认知的力量吗
What you don't think there are forces out there we don't understand?
不这样认为  不  你和我都是科学家
Not really no. you and I are scientists.
我们理应相信眼见和可触碰的事物
We're supposed to believe in what we see and what we touch.
-巧克力  -看吧  力量
- the chocolate! - see? forces.
我不断听到那声音在我脑海里回响
I keep hearing that voice echoing in my head.
我想我要疯了
I think I'm going crazy.
你不会有事的  过来
You're not going crazy. come here.
你不会有事的  你只是
You're not going crazy. you just-
要快点休息
Just need to sleep.
试着睡一下  好吗
Just try to sleep hmm?
混乱  血腥  眼泪
Chaos. blood. tears.
-早上好  神父  -早上好
- morning father. - morning.
我是来见布路卡斯牧师的
I'm here to see monsignor brusca.
你还未得知消息吧
Oh you don't know do you?
在我们找到棺材的第二天他就中风了
He had a stroke the day after we found the coffin.
几分钟他还很清醒  可突然间倒地昏迷
He was conscious for only a few minutes before he slipped into a coma.
很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
听着  我明白现在说这个不合时宜
Look i... understand this isn't the best time...
但我需要了解更多关于骨灰瓮的事
But I really do need to know as much as I can about the urn.
听者  我真的不知道为什么
Look. look I really don't know why...
谁会拿走那个骨灰瓮
Anyone would want to take that urn.
我所知道是一个名字  奥斯卡・德勒
The only thing I know is that there was a name : oscar de la vall?
-奥斯卡・德勒  -是的
- oscar de la vall? - yes.
你知道他是谁吗
Do you know who he was?
牧师认为他就是那个在奥斯塔
The monsignor thought it was the same man...
流传数世纪的古老传说中所描述的人
Who figures in an old story that's been popular in aosta for centuries.
大多数人  包括我  都认为这只是个传说
Most people including me consider it nothing but legend.
布路卡斯却没有  那就是他为什么把东西送到你那去考究
Brusca didn't. that's why he sent the items to you for verification.
好吧  你可以告诉我那个故事吗
Wellcan you tell me about the story?
在1814年
In 1814...
工人们在奥斯塔翻新中世纪教堂
Workers renovating the church curia in aosta...
发现了一个骨灰瓮
Discovered an urn.
里面有几样东西
There were several items inside it...
包括一件可能异教徒时代的缝制裙子
Including a dress that may have been from pagan times.
如同传说一样  就在发现骨灰瓮的第二晚
As the legend has it packs of wolves came out of the forest...
狼群从森林汹涌而出
The night after the urn was found.
它们在墓园撕咬新下葬的死尸
They dug up freshly-buried bodies in the graveyard...
撕得支离破碎
And tore them to bits.
当地牧师决定把骨灰瓮送回梵蒂冈
- the local priest decided to send the urn to the vatican. -
奥斯卡・德勒自愿负责押送它
>oscar de la vall?/i> volunteered to deliver it.
他是个贵族血统的骑士  只有他被允许和教皇说话
He was a knight of noble birth. only he was allowed to talk with the pope.
那是个痛苦的旅程
- he had one bad trip.
无论他到哪  死亡和毁灭都会随之到来
Wherever he went death and destruction followed.
孩子夭折  庄稼烧为灰烬
Children died. crops burned.
整个村庄都被毁灭了
- whole villages were devastated. -
很多城镇都拒绝让他进入
Many towns refused to let >de la vall?enter.
人们生活在惊慌之中
People were in a panic.
当他到达梵蒂冈时  他已变成瞎子  病入膏肓了
By the time he reached viterbo   he was both sick and blind.
教堂把他带了进去
The church took him in.
六天后他死了  可能是死于疟疾
He died six days later. maybe it was malarial fever.
他的尸体被埋葬在秘密的地方
His body was buried in a secret place.
骨灰瓮被安放在他的棺材里并用十字架封上
The urn was chained to his coffin and sealed with crucifixes.
找到骨灰瓮之后  牧师像变了个人
After the urn was found the monsignor was a different person.
他开始胡言乱语
He began talking nonsense.
等等  等等
Wait. wait wait.
好的
-yes-
-他中风后写下这个  -给你
- he was writing this when he had the stroke. - here.
上面写的是骨灰瓮里的东西
It's a list of what was in the urn.
-"母亲  以泪洗面"  -是的  母亲  以泪洗面
- "mater lacrimarum." - mater lacrimarum. yes.
牧师认为骨灰瓮
The monsignor thought the urn...
和里面的物件都有魔力
And its contents were magical...
同属于一个邪恶女巫
That they belonged to an evil witch...
名叫mater lacrimarum  意思为泪水恶灵
Named mater lacrimarum- the mother of tears.
真遗憾
It's such a shame.
他是一个智者  待人亲切
He was a brilliant man- kind...
也是一个好导师
And a wonderful teacher.
终其一生  相信这些毫无意义的东西
To end his days believing in this nonsense-
他跟我说的  想必也跟你说了很多次
I'm sure he told you the same thing he told me many times-
凡人是不能参透上帝的安排  但他例外
That god's plans for us are a mystery to everyone but him.
布路卡斯牧师写下这个  必有他的原因
Monsignor brusca wrote this for a reason.
或许我们不能理解  但是一定有它的意思
One we might not understand but a reason nonetheless.
再见  神父
Good-bye father.
别动  叫你别动
Hold still. I said hold still!
-不  救我  -把腿打开  把腿打开
- no! help me! - open your legs. open your legs!
不  救我
No! help me!
站住  别跑
- stop! freeze!
别动
- freeze! -
米高在吗
Michael?
有人吗
Hello?
有人在家吗
Is there anybody home?
米高
Michael?
保罗
Paul?
米高
Michael?
米高  怎么了
Michael! what happened?
他们抓了他
They took him.
-谁抓了他  -保姆
- who took him? - the babysister...
她说出去两分钟
Went out for two minutes she said.
她回来时
She came back...
发现  这个
And she found... this-
如果想再见到你儿子
"if you want to see your son again...
守口如瓶
Keep the silentium. "
The silentium.
米高  我也很难过
Michael I'm sorry.
亲爱的  我也难过
I'm so sorry darling.
那些符号  和我在骨灰瓮上见到的一样
Those symbols- they are the same ones I saw on the urn.
我知道  是同一班人  同一种黑魔法
I know! it's the same people. it's some kind of black magic.
黑魔法?
Black magic?
-我不知道什么是黑魔法  -什么
- I don't know about black magic- - what?
-什么  你觉得这都是巧合吗
- what   you think this is all some sort of coincidence?
-不  我没那样说
- no   I didn't say-
别那么幼稚  吉塞尔的死
Don't be so bloody naive! giselle's dead.
布路卡斯昏迷不醒  现在他们抓走了保罗
Brusca's in a coma. now they've taken paul.
这一切都和骨灰瓮和那些护符有关
It's - it's all connected with the urn and-and those talismans.
他们要我停止探查  他们要我住嘴
And they want me to stop looking. they want me to keep quiet.
什么  他们让你保密什么
About what? keep quiet about what?
黑暗逐渐侵袭罗马  你感觉不到吗
The darkness... gathering around rome. you haven't seen it?
正在当下  跟我来
It's happening. here come with me!
-听着  让我告诉你  看  -我来了
- look. let me show you. look. - I'm coming.
你觉得这都是什么  在哪里
What do you think all this is? where is it?
-连续自杀  2天内发生52宗  -对
- an epidemic of suicides 52 in two days! - yes.
看  一股暴力浪潮正在城里汹涌着
Look. a wave of violence spreads through the city-
谋杀  纵火  绑架  破坏教会
Murders fires kidnappings church vandalism-
是的  米高  你吓到我了   我知道这一切
Yes michael you're scaring me. - I know all this.
我要去蒙得维的亚  去找约翰内斯神父
I'm going to monteleone. there's a priest there father johannes.
他有什么法宝可以拯救世界
And what on earth could he do to help this situation?
他是个驱魔人  梵蒂冈最后一个获准驱魔人
He's an exorcist- one of the last confirmed by the vatican.
他对超自然的了解比我所认识的所有人都多
He knows more about the occult than anyone else I know.
而他有办法帮我在不被发现的情况下救出保罗
And he'll be able to help me get paul back in a way they can't detect.
-听着  米高  为什么不找警察  -不  不准报警
- look   michael   why don't we try the police? - no! no police!
你看到他们在博物馆怎么看你的
You saw the way they looked at you at the museum.
他们觉得你是个疯子
They thought you were fucking crazy!
米高  听着   我也爱保罗  和你一样爱他
Michael look i-i love paul okay as much as you do...
但我不知道这个是否最好的方法
But I don't know if this is the best way-
他是我的儿子
He is my son!
不是你的
Not yours!
米高
- michael. -
妈的  小心点  妈的
Damn it! be careful damn it!
下地狱受死吧
You rot in hell.
-准备好狂欢了吗  -当然
- are you ready for the celebration? - of course!
打扰了
- excuse me. -
复仇女神三姊妹
Three furies.
复仇
Furies.
三种命运
Three fates.
优雅三女神
Three graces.
黛安娜 三头怪
Diana the three-headed-
三位一体
The triad.
为什么老是三个不停呢
Why are they always three?
抱歉  你好
Sorry. hello?
-萨拉  你好  是我  米高  -米高
- sarah   hi. it's me. it's michael. - michael?
-你在哪  -等等  不  听我说
- where are you? - wait   no   no. wait   wait   listen.
-我需要你的帮忙  好吗  -好的  我当然愿意帮你
- i-i really need your help   okay? - yeah   of course I'll help you.
告诉我该怎么做
Just tell me what to do.
米高
Michael!
你还在吗  米高
Hello are you there? michael!
救我  萨拉  救我
Help me sarah. help me.
米高  你还在吗
Michael are you still there?
米高  米高
Michael? michael!
喂  姐妹
Hey sister.
等一等
Chotomateh!
抓住她
Simone. ikeh!
好吧  我们分散去找她
Okay please come on. let's find her.
别引起太大的注意
And try not to draw too much attention to yourselves   okay?
-好的 我知道  我知道  -好的  你们两个跟着我  这边
- okay I know I know. - okay you two with me. come on. this way.
快点  快点
Move! move!
我们是警察
People we're the police.
不  不  不  你不能进去  不能进去
No no no you can't go in. can't go in.
女士  你也是  过来  谢谢合作
Lady you too. move on please. thank you. move on.
凝神静气
-  concentrate. - huh?
Concentrate!
他们看不到你的
They won't see you!
别担心  他们看不到你的
Don't worry. they won't see you!
我们跟丢了
We lost her.
好吧
Okay.
干什么
What?
请问这趟火车是去哪里的
Excuse me. where's this train going?
-奥托  三十分钟后出发  -谢谢
- orte. leaves in 30 minutes. - thank you.
-米高  -这是米高・皮尔斯的留言信箱
- michael? - this is michael pierce's voicemail.
请在录音后留下口信
- please leave a message after the tone. -
米高  我碰上麻烦了   我现在赶来蒙得维的亚
Michael   I've run into problems. I'm going to monteleone.
再见
Bye.
我能帮你吗
- can I help you? -
抱歉  我听不明白
Sorry I don't understand.
出去
- get out!
去蒙得维的亚的火车将在第九月台出发
The train for monteleone now leaving on track nine.
-她跑哪去了   -说不定在那里
-  where the fuck is she? - maybe in there.
说不定在这里
- maybe she's in there! -
萨拉・曼迪杀了这女人  是因为她看到
Well sarah mandy killed this woman because she saw...
曼迪小姐袭击席尔瓦
Miss mandy attacking da silva over there.
就这样简单
As simple as that.
曼迪小姐体重大约110磅吧
Mandy weighs 110 pounds at the most?
但是  天啊  席尔瓦是一只大猩猩
Da silva god rest his soul was a fucking gorilla.
而且他带有佩枪
And he was armed.
不  这案子比我们想的复杂
No there's more to this case than we think.
把证物收集好  带回去
Can you move them back please?
-什么事  -你好
- yes? - hello?
我是萨拉・曼迪   我在找我一个朋友  他叫米高・皮尔斯
My name is sarah mandy. I'm looking for a friend of mine michael pierce.
-他是来找约翰内斯神父的  -抱歉  他不在这
- he came to see father johannes. - no I'm sorryhe's not here.
什么
What?
我可以见见约翰内斯神父吗  有要紧的事情
Could I see father johannes then? it's very important.
你得明天再来
You have to come back tomorrow.
-他今天不能见你  -抱歉  但那不可能
- he can't see you today. - I'm sorry but that's not possible.
拜托了  告诉他我不会花他太多时间的
Please tell him I won't take much of his time.
拜托了
Please.
好吧  进来
All right.come in.
谢谢  非常谢谢你
Thanks. thanks a lot.
长途跋涉  你看上去很劳累
You look like you had a hard trip.
真像  你知道吗
You have it you know.
你和你母亲的眼神
Your mother's gaze.
你是伊莉莎・曼迪的女儿  对吗
You're elisa mandy's daughter   aren't you?
我是玛塔・古鲁丝
I'm marta colussi.
你和她长得很像
You really look just like her.
很多年前我在德国和你母亲相识
I knew your mother many years ago in germany.
她是个很好的老师
She was a wonderful teacher.
在她身上  我获益良多
I learned so much from her.
她是我所认识的最伟大的降神师
She was a great spiritualist- the best I've ever known.
-我母亲是个舞者  -还是个医疗者
- my mother was a dancer. - and a healer.
或者说是白巫师
A white witch if you will.
就我看来  你从她那里继承了一些天赋
And it seems to me you've inherited some of her gifts.
-听着  女士  -我叫玛塔
- listen lady- - it's marta.
玛塔  无论你是谁
Marta. whoever you are...
我不认识你而我也不是来找你的
I don't know you and I didn't come here to talk to you.
可以离我远点吗
Please leave me alone now   okay?
你是怎么逃出火车站的
How did you get away at the train station?
什么  你是谁
What the-who are you?
伊莉莎在帮你  指引你  不是吗
Elisa was helping you. coaching you   wasn't she?
我不知道
- I don't know.
我听到  我听到一把声音
I heard- I heard a voice.
-你真的认识我母亲吗  -相当熟
- did you really know my mother? - quite well.
-你不太了解她  对吗 -是的
- you don't know much about her   do you? - no.
关于我父母  我不记得很多了
I don't remember much about my parents.
他们死于意外的时候我还很小
I was very young when they died in the accident.
那发生在弗赖堡的车祸
The car crash in freiburg.
不  亲爱的  我很抱歉  事实并不如此
No   honey. I'm sorry. that's not what happened.
你父母是被谋杀的
Your parents were murdered.
什么  你在说什么
What? what are you talking about?
没人和我说过
Nobody ever told me this.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
你母亲勇于反抗强大的黑女巫
Your mother dared to fight the very powerful black witch
"mater suspiriorum“  叹息恶灵
Mater suspiriorum the mother of sighs.
叹息恶灵
The mother of sighs.
约翰内斯神父
Father johannes.
-多少滴  -20滴  麻烦了
- how many drops? - twenty please.
你看起来很疲劳  你需要休息
You look exhausted. you need to rest.
事情进行得如何  我得战斗
With everything that's going on now? I have to fight.
-我得战斗  -冷静  快吃药
- I have to fight! - stay calm now. please. take your drops.
你的弱点是你的体力  神父
Your weakness is your strength father.
我知道你会来的
I've been expecting you.
-你是萨拉  -是的
- you're sarah. - yes.
你好
Hi.
我有很多关于你母亲的事要告诉你
There's a lot I have to tell you-about your mother...
关于你的事  还有关于一个世界
About you and about a world-
你不知道的世界
You hardly know.
千年之前
More than a thousand years ago...
在黑海旁有三姐妹巫术诞生
Witchcraft was birthed...
在黑海旁有三姐妹
By the shores of the black sea by three sisters.
她们四处流浪
For years they roamed the earth...
死亡和毁灭伴随着她们的足迹而来
Bringing death and destruction wherever they went.
查看任何插图史书  都会有她们的肖像
Search any art history book and you'll find images of them.
最后  她们找到了落脚点
Eventually they found homes.
"mater suspiriorum"  叹息恶灵  定居在弗赖堡
Mater suspiriorum   the mother of sighs   settled in freiburg.
罪罚恶灵  "mater tenebrarum"  去了纽约
The mother of pain   mater tenebrarum   went to new york.
mater lacrimarum来到罗马
Mater lacrimarum came to rome.
她是泪水恶灵
She's known as the mother of tears.
她是三人中最残暴也是最美丽的
She's the most cruel and beautiful of the three.
而她也是唯一尚在人间的
And she's the only one still alive.
罪罚恶灵和叹息恶灵
Mater tenebrarum and mater suspiriorum...
在很多年前就死了
Died many years ago.
叹息恶灵  她杀了我父母
The mother of sighs. she murdered my parents.
是的  但在你母亲和她战斗前
Yes. but not before your mother...
她已元气大伤
Had injured her horribly.
在和你母亲搏斗后  她被退化成一个贝壳  这是她的本身
After fighting your mother she was reduced to a shell of her former self.
一个年亲的舞者   名叫苏茜・班尼恩
A young dancer named suzy bannion...
最后成功杀了她
Finally managed to kill her.
但这都是历史
But that's all history.
但布路卡斯发现了那个骨灰瓮  并打开了它
When that urn brusca found was opened...
那就恢复了泪水恶灵的能力
It restored the mother of tears's powers.
你怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
你的朋友  米高  告诉我的
Your friend michael told me about it...
但他打电话来提及魔法红色短上衣
When he phoned and spoke of a magic red tunic...
那是个威力强大的护符
That would be a great and powerful talisman.
我有预感  女巫要归来了
I've had visions. witches are coming...
全世界都在庆祝她的回归
From all over the world to celebrate her return.
对  每天都有人到罗马
Yes. They're arriving in rome every day.
每架飞机  每辆车...
Every jet   every car...
每辆火车  都带来更多她的人
Every train brings more.
他们想让罗马再次堕落...
They aim to make rome fall again...
并以此来让她复活
To usher in the second age of witches.
我没法继续了  我感觉自己要疯了
I can't take it anymore. I feel like I'm going crazy.
萨拉  你的想法并没错
There's nothing wrong with your mind   sarah.
是这个世界变得疯狂了
It's the world that's gone crazy.
来看看吧
Have a look.
看看这个
Look at this.
通常我一个月出去驱一次邪
Usually I have one exorcism request a month...
但近几天同类事件一发不可收拾
But the last few days   I've had more cases than I've had in my whole life.
我认识的每一个牧师  都面临着同样的挑战
Every priest I talk to is faced with the same challenge.
是什么造成这种情况
Why is all this happening?
泪水恶灵在肆意的散播邪恶
The mother of tears spreads evil wherever she can.
要么她杀了你  要么让你疯狂
Some she kills   others she drives mad.
她让人在纵欲中迷失自己
She revels in chaos and human despair.
我们有活儿干了
We have work to do.
这儿有本书也许对我们有帮助
I have a book in my study that shows us the way.
瓦莱里娅  瓦莱里娅
Valeria! valeria!
瓦莱里娅
Valeria.
安息吧
Requiescat!
约翰内斯神父
Father johannes!
-母亲  -玛塔  过来  过来
-Mother? -Marta   come back! come back!
以你之名  妈妈
Mother   I obeyed you!
快点  走吧
Come on   let's go!
让我...救救我...
Let me... Somebody help...
玛塔  玛塔  救命
Marta! marta   help me!
上帝啊
Oh   my god!
玛塔  玛塔  快走啊
Marta! marta   let's go!
-你车在哪儿  -就在那儿
-Where's your car? -It's right there.
他们追上来了  上帝  快点
They're coming! oh   god   run!
-门锁住了  -打开  快打开啊
-It's locked! -Open open up!
-快打开  -我找不到钥匙了
-Open it! -I can't find my key!
为什么他们总缠着我
Why were they all after me?
因为你妈妈
Your mother.
-你在干什么  -我打给米高
-What are you doing? -I'm calling michael.
你疯了吗  他们能通过这个追踪你
Are you crazy? they can trace you with it.
你说得对  去他妈的
You're right. fuck it.
今晚到我家去  那儿暂时是安全的
Come to my place tonight. it'll be safer for you.
不  我要回家
No   I'd rather go home.
米高能在那儿找到我
Michael can reach me there.
这是我的号码和地址
Here's my phone number and address.
-有需要的话随时打给我  -谢谢
-Call me anytime. it's no bother. -Thank you.
你是伊莉莎的女儿  我待你如家人了
You're elisa's daughter. that's closer than family.
不是我想吓唬你  但...
I don't mean to scare you   but...
他们知道你是谁  萨拉
They know who you are   sarah.
向我保证  你不会轻信任何人
Promise me you won't trust anyone.
我保证
I promise.
发生什么了
What's going on here?
他们在焚烧教堂
They are burning the churches.
形势正在恶化
It's getting worse.
母亲  母亲
Mater! mater!
有什么东西在我房间里
There was somebody at my apartment!
我从门缝里看到有人影  我简直快疯了
I saw lights and shadows under the door. I feel like I'm going crazy!
上帝啊  救救我  求你救救我
God! help. please help me. help me   please.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
-谢谢  -冷静下来
-Thank you. -Calm down.
进来吧
Come in.
-艾嘉  这是萨拉  -你好
-Elga   meet sarah. -Hi.
-她在这儿干什么  -没事的
-What is she doing here? -It's okay.
玛塔  你必须得帮帮我  我也不知道自己究竟怎么了
Marta   you have to help me. I don't know what's happening to me.
-跟我来  -你得帮帮我
-Come with me. -You have to explain.
为什么这一切都发生在我身上  为什么
Why is all this happening to me? why?
他们知道你是谁  他们不会放过你
They know who you are. they can't take any chances.
但我  我什么都不知道啊
But l- l- I don't know anything.
你所知道的  远超过你的想象
You know more than you think you do.
想想为何你总能从那些怪物手中逃脱
How else have you survived this long with those monsters after you?
艾嘉  能出去一下吗
Elga would you please excuse us for a minute?
求你  好吗
Oh please. come on.
行吗
Please?
你有常人所没有的天赋
You have gifts sarah.
如果你想活下来  就必须学会接受这一切
You need to accept that if you want to survive.
看着  好好学
Watch and learn.
漂泊幽灵
Drifting spirits.
他们无处不在  尤其是罗马
They are everywhere especially here in rome
老房子里到处是幽灵
The old houses are full of ghosts.
想想吧
Think about it.
这座城市已经有2700年的历史了...
The city is 2700 years old...
而且我们脚下是五层的坟墓
And we are standing on five layers of graves.
-你是怎么做到的  -你也可以
-How do you do it? -You can do it too.
因为你的天赋  你可以看到别人看不到的东西
With your gifts you can see what others can't.
闭上眼
Close your eyes.
集中你所有的精力
Focus all of your energy...
聚集在这一点
And concentrate on this spot.
很好
Good.
现在照我刚才的做一遍
Now just do like I did and blow.
萨拉
Sarah.
不  这不可能
No it can't be.
妈妈
Mommy?
萨拉
Sarah.
-妈妈  -别碰她  否则她会消失
-Mommy! -You can't touch her or she'll disappear.
别拉着我
Leave me alone.
泪水恶灵越来越强大了  她越来越强了  萨拉
Mater lacrimarum grows stronger. she grows stronger   sarah!
你...你到哪儿去了
Where-where are you?
妈妈  妈妈
Mommy! mommy!
你正身处险境  我的宝贝儿
You're in great danger   my dear child.
-学会战斗  -不
-Learn to fight. -No!
不  不
No! no!
别走  妈妈  别丢下我  妈妈
Don't go   mommy! don't leave me! mommy   please!
妈妈
Mommy!
让她回来  求你了
Please make her come back. please!
别丢下我  别丢下我
Don't leave me. don't leave.
她叫我学会战斗
She told me to fight.
你得帮我  我要战斗  求你
You have to help me. I have to fight. please.
我只是个通灵师
I'm only a psychic.
我能和幽灵交流  但也仅限于此
I can communicate with spirits   but that's about it.
我没有你或你妈妈那样的天赋
I don't have your mother's gifts   or yours.
你需要一个合适的导师  一个能引导你的人
You need someone who can guide you   point you in the right direction.
对
Yes.
明天我会把你介绍给格里艾努・迪・维特
Tomorrow I'll introduce you to guglielmo de witt.
-他是位伟大的比利时冥想家  -好的
-He's a great belgian thinker. -Okay.
他会帮上忙的  如果还不算太晚的话
He'll tell you something useful   if it's not too late.
谢谢
Thank you.
不  不
No. no.
快接啊
Pick up the phone.
快点  玛塔  快接啊
Come on   marta   pick up the phone!
是你吗  玛塔
Hello? hello   marta?
玛塔  你必须离开那儿  是你吗  玛塔
Marta   you have to get out of there now! marta? hello? who's there?
快跑  太迟了
Run! it's too late!
快点  快跑
Now! run now!
不  她什么都不知道
No! she doesn't know anything!
不要  不要啊
No! don't do it! don't do it!
母亲  母亲
Mater! mater!
萨拉在哪里
Where is sarah?
她不在这儿
She isn't here.
蠢货
Idiot!
是你
It is you.
原来是你
It is.
坚强点  坚强
Stay strong. stay strong!
-妈妈  -你得学会坚强  萨拉
-Mom. -Stay strong   sarah!
好的
Yes.
妈妈  当时他们对你和爸爸做了什么
Mom what did they do to you and dad when...
那些都过去了
Shh. it's all in the past.
你对此也无能为力  这样毫无意义
There's nothing you can do. it was meant to be.
曾经我很恨你  因为你就那样离我而去
I was so upset   so angry at you for leaving me.
求你  求你别再丢下我
Plea- please don't abandon me again.
原谅我  小萨拉
Forgive me little sarah.
我不能说更多了
I can't speak anymore.
你我已不再在同一个世界  好好利用你的天赋
I belong to another place now. use your gifts.
利用它  用它
Use them. use them.
妈妈
Mommy.
伙计们听着  我们在找一个28岁左右的女孩
Okay   guys   listen up. we're looking for a girl around 28.
她叫萨拉・曼迪  如果你们见到她  别惊动她
Her name is sarah mandy. if you see her   don't approach her.
米高
Michael?
Michael.
米高  米高
Michael! michael!
米高 等等
Michael   stop!
米高
Michael?
Michael.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
米高  你病了
Michael   you're sick.
保罗在哪里
Where's paul?
我以为...
I thought...
你...
Did you...
我想...
I think...
我想...我想他已经死了
I think he's... I think he's dead.
-上帝啊  -他们杀了他
-Oh   my god. -They killed him.
-上帝  -我不能...
-Oh my god. -And I can't...
现在我不想谈这个
I don't want to talk about that now.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我的公寓现在也不安全
My apartment is not safe.
-我去的每一个地方  他们都...  -那去我家
-Everywhere I go   they... -We'll go to my place.
他们不会找到那儿的
They won't look for you there.
不  不  别开灯
No   no. no lights.
为什么
Why?
我不想他们发现我们
We don't want them to see us.
真高兴我们还能碰见
I'm so happy we found each other.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-为什么不脱掉衣服躺下来休息一下  -不  不
-Why don't you just rest   take off your coat -No   no   no.
我浑身冰冷  抱歉  我太冷了
I'm freezing. sorry. I'm freezing.
我没法再一个人呆一晚上了
I just haven't spent a- a single night inside.
-为找他我跑遍了每个角落  -发生什么事了
-I looked everywhere for him. -Yeah   what happened?
-因为我到蒙得维的亚去找你  -我去不了那里
-Because I went to monteleone to find you. -I couldn't get there.
他们跟踪我
They were following me.
现在我明白你以前所说的是什么意思了
Everything you were trying to tell me I understand now.
很抱歉我以前没有相信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
没什么
Okay.
也许你不该吸烟
Maybe you shouldn't smoke.
为何你不...
Why don't you...
想要点什么喝的吗  茶怎么样
Do you want me to fix something? Tea   maybe?
不要
No.
不要  我很好
No   I'm f- I'm fine.
只是...
I'm just...
我只是很高兴能再见到你
I'm just pleased I found you again.
我很好  你别担心
I'm fine. don't worry. fine.
米高  你在流血
Michael   you're bleeding!
-这没什么  -米高  你受伤了
-It's nothing. -Michael   you're hurt!
不  没...没什么
No   it's... it's okay.
这没关系
It's nothing.
没关系是什么意思  你受伤了
What do you mean   it's nothing? you're hurt!
我说了没什么  别碰我
I told you it's nothing! get off me!
我他妈的叫你别碰我
I told you to get the fuck off me!
你觉得他们会放过我和我的孩子吗
Do you think they would spare me and my child?
你太幼稚了
You're so naive.
你逃不出她的手掌心的
You can't escape her.
但他们杀了你的儿子
But they killed your son!
你妈妈现在帮不了你了
Your mother can't help you anymore.
现在  我们只有一个母亲
We all have one mother now.
泪水恶灵
The mother of tears.
疯狗  你疯了
You bitch! oh   you crazy
你这只疯狗
You crazy bitch!
记住玛塔给你说的那个名字  格里艾努
Guglielmo. the name marta gave you.
去找他
Find him.
妈妈
Mommy!
萨拉
Sarah!
欢迎回到早间新闻
Welcome back to the morning news.
现在播报每日要闻
And now for today's top story.
罗马的第二次堕落来临了
They're calling it the second fall of rome.
在过去的几天里
Over the past few days the city has
这座城市见证了数百起暴行
Witnessed hundreds of acts of violence.
马奇i探员  这些案件彼此间都有联系吗
Detective marchi   you say that they are all connected?
是的
Uh   yes.
这一系列事件都起源于罗马博物馆的一件案子
Everything started with events at the art museum of rome.
助理馆长吉赛尔・马雷斯的谋杀案
The brutal murder of the assistant curator   giselle mares.
但这些又是如何联系起来的
But how does that all tie together?
那件谋杀案是现在所有案子的导火索
It was the trigger for everything that's happening now.
我们建议每位公民留意下面这位女子 萨拉・曼迪
We ask everybody to be on the lookout for this girl   sarah mandy...
博物馆谋杀案的唯一目击证人
The only witness to events at the museum.
-如果有人看见她...  -她是这案子的嫌疑犯吗
-If you see her... -Is she a suspect?
如果有人看见他  请千万不要靠近她
If you see her   do not approach her.
马上打电话到重案组报警
Call the police and ask to speak to homicide.
他妈的
Shit!
-去你的  -不  去你的
-Fuck you! -Oh   no   fuck you!
-把我的钱给我  -你在说些什么
-Give me my money! -What are you talking about?
把你车给我  把你的车给我
Give me your car. give me your car!
太阳眼镜
Sunglasses!
不  不
No! no! no!
你好
Hello?
对  能给我格里艾努・迪・维特先生的地址吗
Yes   can I please have the address for Mr.guglielmo de witt?
d e w l t t
D-e-w-l-double t.
-找谁  -我要见格里艾努・迪・维特
-Yes? -I need to see guglielmo de witt.
你是?
And you are?
他并不认识我
My name won't mean anything to him.
好吧  进来
All right. come in.
就是你要见我吗
So   you wanted to see me?
请坐吧
Please sit down.
如你所见  我行动不大方便
As you can see   l- I'm not very mobile.
我来是因为...是因为有些事要问你...
I'm here because I... I have to ask you about...
也许炼金术士是个古老的职业
We alchemists may practice an ancient art...
但我们也会看新闻
But we do watch the news.
你认为我不知道你是谁吗  萨拉・曼迪
Do you think I wouldn't know who you are   sarah mandy?
好像警察因为你涉及谋杀  在到处找你吧
And that the police is looking for you because you're wanted for murder?
关于我们炼金术士还有一点...
Another thing about us alchemists...
我们从不盲从
We're not all one thing or another.
毕竟好的魔法就是好的魔法  而黑魔法...
After all   good magic is good   and black magic is...
同样很不错
Well   it's good too.
象魔法  科学
Some of what we do is magic   science...
秘术  通灵学  以及自然法则
Esoterism   theosophy   natural law.
我们或多或少都有涉猎
A little of this and a little of that.
这会让我看清你到底是什么
This will let me know who you really are...
以及你看到过什么
And what you've really seen.
很有趣
Hmm. interesting.
你有很大的潜力
I see you have latent powers.
甚至可以说天赋过人
Instinct more than anything else.
是玛塔・古鲁丝叫你来的吧
Marta colussi sent you   I see.
而你的妈妈  伊莉莎・曼迪
So did your mother   elisa mandy.
你对我做了什么
What did you do to me? huh?
你想让我在没弄清你是谁之前
Did you expect me to just let you waltz
就贸然行事吗
In here without making sure who you are?
现在  说说你到这儿来的目的吧
Now   why exactly did you come here?
我要找到泪水恶灵
I need to find the mother of tears.
-为什么  -找到这一切罪恶的根源
-Why? -Look what's happening to the city.
罗马正在走向黑暗  我们必须得阻止她
Rome is falling apart. she has to be stopped.
那你认为你能做些什么  杀了她吗
Mmm. what do you think you can do? kill her?
我妈妈曾经是位强大的巫师
Well   my mother was very powerful...
我认为我具有与她一样的天赋
And I think I might have the same gifts.
你什么时候才发现你的天赋  昨天吗
Which you found out about when? yesterday?
我也不知道
I don't know.
一定有人能帮助我们的  比如我妈妈
There's got to be some people that can help   people like my mother.
约翰内斯神父说...
Father johannes said that...
泪水恶灵正为自己的复活做准备
That mater lacrimarum is bringing on the second age of witches.
约翰内斯神父说得很对
Mmm. father johannes was right.
在这座城市的某个角落里  仪式已经开始了
Somewhere in the city the celebration has already begun.
但恐怕没有强有力的
But I'm afraid there is no army of good
巫师军团去阻止这一切
Witches out there to come to the rescue.
如果你想阻止她  你只能靠你自己
If you want to stop her   you have to do it yourself.
意思是说你会袖手旁观了
So I'm on my own now?
我并没说我不会帮你
I didn't say I wouldn't help.
我不能给你答案  但可以给你找到答案的钥匙
I can't give you answers   but I can share information.
跟我来
Follow me.
几个世纪前  罗马出了一位叫瓦内里的伟大炼金术士
Centuries ago   a great roman alchemist named varelli...
他在世时就住在这栋别墅
Lived for a time in this villa.
同时  他也是一位天才的建筑师
He was also a gifted architect.
在他生命的最后几年
And near the end of his life
他建造了三位女神的神庙
He built the residences for the three mothers.
也许你会在其中找到答案
This may tell you something you need to know.
三位圣母
The three mothers.
我不知道打破炼金术士们所谓的"缄默"
I don't know how much it will cost me...
会让我付出什么样的代价
To break what we alchemists have always called silentium.
我有幸遇到了三位圣母
I met the three mothers...
并为她们建造了三座神庙
And built three houses for them.
一座在弗赖堡  一座在纽约
One in freiburg   one in new york...
还有一座在罗马
And one in rome.
当我发现这三座神庙中隐藏的邪恶与淫亵时  为时已晚
I discovered too late that these houses hide obscene secrets.
幽灵姐妹们就是从这儿  向整个世界
It is from here that the sisters spread pain...
散播痛苦  黑暗  以及罪恶
Tears and darkness throughout the world.
这应该是瓦内里在罗马建造的那座
This building should be the one varelli built in rome.
你看到的
"what you see...
全是虚无
"does not exist...
看不到的  才真正存在
And what you cannot see is truth. "
这是句偈语
It's a riddle.
能帮助你找到恶灵之类的老巢
Find where mater lacrimarum resides...
我想你会找出答案的
And you'll find the answer.
你真的决意如此吗
Are you sure you want to do this?
我别无退路
Do I have a choice?
母亲
Mater.
停  停在这儿
Stop. stop right here!
你是谁
Hey! who are you?
我...我刚刚看到几个女人走进来
I... I just saw some women come in.
-你看到她们了吗  -没有
-Did you see them? -No.
-你是来采访我的吗  -对
-You here to interview me? -Yeah.
给你
Here.
你在这儿住了多久了
How long you've been living here?
很久了
Shh-a long time.
三  四十年吧
Thirty   forty years.
自从二战结束纳粹倒台开始就在这儿了
Since the nazis escaped at the end of the war.
那你之前是谁住这儿呢
And who used to live here before you?
我也不知道  好像是个什么社团
Oh   I don't know. a kind of association.
哲学  还是艺术来着  不记得了
Philosophers. artists maybe. I don't remember.
为什么他们会离开这地方
Why did they leave?
也许是因为纳粹占据了这里
Maybe because when the nazis occupied the villa...
在地下室拷问  逼供那些可怜的人
They tortured and killed a lot of people down here.
你不会去举报我吧
Hey! you won't report me   will ya?
放松
Easy.
-她到哪儿去了  -也许走了
-Where did she go? -I think she's gone.
我上楼去找找
I'll check upstairs.
-待在这儿  -好
-Stay here. -Yeah.
-没找到  -那她就走了  一切正常
-She's not there! -Then she's gone. everything's okay.
你忘了我们是干什么的吧  对吗
You forgot what we were supposed to do   didn't you?
-没有  -是吗
-No. -No?
一旦有人来  就马上报告我们
Inform them every time somebody comes to look around!
-听懂了吗  -听懂了
-Understand? -Yes!
-听懂了  -滚
-Yes. -Move!
-他们去哪儿了  刚刚...-嘘
-Where did they go? they just... -Shh.
他们在这儿  我能感觉到
They're in here. I can feel it.
你看到的  全是虚无
"what you see does not exist...
看不见的  才真正存在
And what you cannot see is truth. "
神庙之秘
The secret of the house.
这些符号和我在骨灰瓮上看到的一模一样
Those are the same symbols I saw on the urn.
地下陵墓
Catacombs.
这是未被人知的地下陵墓
These are unexplored catacombs.
上帝啊
Oh   my god.
这就是泪水恶灵
This is the home of the mother of tears...
和她追随者们的老巢
And her followers.
上帝
Dear god.
这么多女巫
Witches.
女巫
Witches?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
很快你就知道了
You'll see.
跟在我后面
Stay behind me.
三美神之舞
The three graces.
你在这儿做什么
What are you doing down here?
我是个美术史学家  我只想来看看...
I'm an art historian. I just wanted to see...
那就跟我们来  我会让你看个够的
Come with us. I'll let you see something.
让你看个够  看个够
We'll show you! yeah! we'll show you!
来吧
Come on!
(一种古代语言)
In ancient language
圣母  赐与我们力量吧
Mother   give us power!
烧光它
Burn it all!
我会的  我会的
I will! I will!
我会的
I will!
圣母  圣母
Mater! mater!
Mater! Mater!
看啊  圣母  一个闯入者
Look   mother! an intruder!
等等
Wait!
抓住他
Get him!
生吃了他
We'll eat you alive!
把他挂起来
Hang him!
我们的时代...
Our hour...
来临了
Is coming!
你好啊  萨拉
Hello   sarah.
到这儿来
Come here.
(一种古代语言)
In ancient language
谁想尝尝这女孩
Who wants to eat the girl?
我
Me.
为了这一时刻
We have waited for this moment...
我们等了一千年
For one thousand years!
这儿是我们的力量之源
Our power is here!
没人能阻止我们
No one can stop us now!
没人
No one!
不
No!
-该死  -这儿要塌了
-Damn you! -It's an earthquake!
不
No!
萨拉
Sarah!
是我  是我  是我
Shh! shh! it's me   it's me! it's me! it's me!
我们走  我们走
Come on. come on.
恩佐  恩佐
Enzo. enzo!
快走  快走
Go. go! go!